printful.com 2019-06-23

# Privacy Policy | Printful

Welcome to Printful’s Privacy Policy!

Printful respects the privacy of its users and is fully committed to protect their personal data and use it in accordance with legal obligations. This Privacy Policy describes how we may collect and use personal data and the rights granted to our visitors, customers, and merchants regarding their respective data.

By accessing or using this website, mobile app or any of our Services, you signify your approval of the terms set out in this Privacy Policy, Cookie Policy, Terms of Service, and other terms and policies posted on our website. If you do not agree to this Privacy Policy, you must leave this website and discontinue all use of any of our Services.

### 1\. Information we collect

#### 1\. 1. Information collected from Merchants

If you are providing us with personal data relating to another individual, you are to be considered as a Merchant, where data are processed as follows.

If you are a Merchant, you agree to comply with data protection laws applicable to your business. Furthermore, you agree that you acquire legal basis for the processing of personal data of your Customer, including, but not limited to, the use and access of the respective personal data by Printful and other third parties used by Printful for the provision of its Services.

What information do we collect from Merchants?

We collect the following data to confirm your identity, contact you, invoice you, and otherwise provide our Services.

  * Company name
  * Address
  * Email address and phone number
  * Payment details

To give you access and to improve our Services, we may collect data about:

  * How and when you access your account
  * Information about the device and browser you use
  * Your network connection
  * Your IP address

For us to be able to provide you our Services and support, to process orders, for you to better serve your Customers, and to improve our Services, we collect information about your Customers:

  * Name, surname, company name
  * Shipping and billing address
  * Email address and phone number
  * IP address and device data
  * Other information that you share with us or that customers provide while using our Services or during checkout

When you give us your permission, we might use personal data for other purposes as well.

Upon starting to use our Services we may process your email address to send you informative materials, such as newsletters, advertisements and others. At any point in time you can unsubscribe from receiving the above-mentioned information in our email footers and through your notification settings on Printful. We will not use the contact details of your Customers to directly advertise our Services to them.

#### 1\. 2. Information collected from our Users

If you use our Services to place personal orders without processing the data of third parties, you are to be considered as the User, where data are processed as follows.

What information do we collect from Users?

We collect the following data to confirm your identity, contact you, invoice you, and otherwise provide our Services.

  * Name, surname, company name
  * Shipping and billing address
  * Email address and phone number
  * Payment details
  * IP address and device data
  * Other information that you share with us while using our Services or during checkout

We collect the above-mentioned personal data when the User uses or accesses our Services, places an order, or signs up for an account on our website or mobile app.

Upon starting to use our Services or when you subscribe to our blog or newsletters, we may process your email address to send you informative materials. At any point in time you can unsubscribe from receiving the above-mentioned information in our email footers and through your notification settings on Printful.

#### 1\. 3. Information collected from Printful website visitors and users

Upon visiting our website, requesting customer support, or subscribing to our blog, we may collect and process the following information related to you.

What information do we collect from website visitors?

To provide you with a better customer experience and to improve our Services, we may collect the following information about:

  * Your device and browser
  * Your IP address
  * Other information that is collected from cookies and similar technology we use. Learn more about how we use cookies on our website.

To ensure a smooth customer support experience, we process information that you provide on our website (eg. in chat or on the comment section of our blog), in emails, or through other means of communication you have used. For this purpose, we may process:

  * Your name
  * Email address
  * Website address
  * Any information that you share
  * IP address

We use this information to provide and enhance our Services and answer any questions you may have.

### 2\. Sharing personal data with third parties

In order for Printful to provide you with our Services, we work with third parties with whom we may share personal data to support these Services. Your personal data may be shared with third parties who provide hosting and server co-location services, communications and content delivery networks, data and cyber security services, billing and payment processing services, fraud detection and prevention services, web analytics, email distribution and monitoring services, session recording services, marketing services, our legal and financial advisors, among others (together – “Third Party Service Providers”). The Third Party Service Providers may only receive the minimum amount of personal data necessary, depending on their particular roles and purposes in facilitating and enhancing our Services and business, and may only use it for such purposes. We will only share personal data to Third Party Service Providers that have undertaken to comply with obligations set out in applicable data protection laws.

Note that while our Service may contain links to other websites or services, we are not responsible for each respective website’s or service’s privacy practices, and encourage you to be aware when you leave our Services and read the privacy statements of each and every website and service you visit. This Privacy Policy does not apply to third-party websites and services.

If you are a Merchant, by using our Services you are providing us with irrevocable consent to use any Third Party Service Provider at our discretion for the purposes of providing the Service.

Printful remains responsible for the processing of personal data carried out by Third Party Service Providers that Printful has engaged with for respective data processing in accordance with applicable laws.

In certain circumstances, we may also be required to share information with third parties to conform to legal requirements or to respond to lawful requests by public authorities as well as to protect our, or a third party’s, lawful interests.

### 3\. Retention periods

We may retain your personal data, as well as your Customers' information, for as long as your relationship with us is active by having a Printful account, or as otherwise needed to provide you our Services.

After terminating your relationship with us by deleting your Printful account or otherwise ceasing to use our Services, we may continue to store copies of your and your Customers’ personal data as reasonably necessary to comply with our legal obligations, to resolve disputes between you and us or you and your Customers, to prevent fraud and abuse, to enforce our agreements, and/or to protect our legitimate interests.

### 4\. Data subject's rights

If you are located in the European Economic Area, in accordance with European Union data protection regulations, you have certain rights with respect to your personal data.

You have the right to request access to your personal data and to correct, amend, delete, or limit the use of your personal data by logging into your Printful account or by reaching us using the contact information provided below. Furthermore, if you believe that we have unlawfully processed your personal data, you have the right to submit a complaint to the contact information provided below, or to your respective data protection supervisory authority. If you are the Customer of a Merchant, please contact the Merchant to exercise your data subject’s rights stated above.

### 5\. Information security

We seek to use reasonable organizational, technical, and administrative measures to protect the confidentiality, integrity, and availability of personal data. Unfortunately, no data transmission or storage system is guaranteed to be 100% secure, therefore we cannot guarantee absolute security of information. We encourage you to take care of the personal data in your possession that you process online and set strong passwords for your Printful account, limit access of your computer and browser by signing off after you have finished your session, and avoid providing us with any sensitive information whose disclosure you believe could cause you substantial harm.

All of Printful’s authorized personnel involved in the processing of your and your Customer’s personal data have committed themselves to confidentiality obligations and shall not access or otherwise process your personal data without your authorization if it's not for the purposes of providing you our Services.

In the event that we experience a personal data breach, we will notify you (as a Merchant or a User) in compliance with the obligations set out in applicable laws.

### 6\. International transfers of data

All the information you provide may be transferred or accessed by Printful, its affiliated companies and subsidiaries around the world for the provision of our Services as described in this Privacy Policy. When we transfer your information globally we will take necessary measures to ensure adequate protection of your information.

### 7\. Privacy Policy changes

This Policy shall be governed and interpreted in accordance with the English language, regardless of any translations made for any purpose whatsoever.

We may occasionally amend this Privacy Policy, for example in cases when we introduce new services or new features. The amendments to this Privacy Policy enter into force and are applied from the moment they have been uploaded to this page.

Therefore, we encourage you to check this page from time to time. By continuing to use our Services or otherwise providing personal data to us, after the amendments to this policy have been implemented, you agree to the updated terms of Privacy Policy.

### 8\. Contact information

If you have any questions about your personal data or this Privacy Policy, or if you would like to file a complaint about how we process your personal data, please contact us by email at privacy@printful.com, or by using the contact details below:
